<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<articles>
	<article>
		<title>
			<h1>Flyleaf announce front-woman Lacey Sturm has left the band.</h1>
		</title>
		<header>
			<h2>This news comes one week before the release of their much
			anticipated third album entitled “New Horizons.” The title 
			track, which has already gained a large amount of national
			airplay, has been well received by both fans and critics alike</h2>
		</header>
		<video>
			"latest/article1.mp4" type="video/mp4"
		</video>
		<caption>
			New Flyleaf Song - New Horizons
		</caption>
		<body>
			<p>The remaining members of the band Sameer Bhattacharya, 
			Jared Hartmann, James Culpepper, and Pat Seals will be 
			continuing on and touring in support of “New Horizons” 
			with replacement vocalist Kristen May (formerly of the 
			band Vedera).</p>

			<p>Flyleaf enjoyed platinum-selling success of their self-titled 
			debut album, which was released on October 4th, 2005. Singles 
			such as “I’m So Sick,” “All Around Me,” and “Fully Alive” helped 
			to keep the momentum of the debut alive for more than three years
			and propelling the band the forefront of the dismal selling rock
			genre. The follow-up, 2009’s “Memento Mori” wasn’t as well received
			as their debut but gained a great deal of success in its own right 
			producing singles such as “Missing” and “Arise.” Flyleaf has also 
			released three EPs since the release of their debut album along 
			with a tremendous cover of Nine Inch Nails’ “Something I Can Never
			Have” on the soundtrack for the film “Underworld.”</p>

			<p>“New Horizons” is scheduled for release on October 30th,
			2012. Lacey Sturm’s stage presence, raw emotion, and range 
			between ‘a sweet voice’ and ‘a low roar of anger’ will be 
			sorely missed in the rock world. She is one of the few singers
			that can make a listener actually ‘feel’ what she is singing and
			the meaning of each song therein by pure showmanship and delivery.
			She is a true talent that will never be easily duplicated.</p>

			<p>There is no indication that Lacey Sturm will continue a 
			career in music. However, she hasn’t been afraid to venture 
			outside of the world of Flyleaf in the past contributing a
			solo track to a recent film and collaborating with both Orianthi
			and Apocalyptica. That being said, there is a possibility the 
			final chapter has yet to be written on the career this wonderful
			performer and songwriter.</p>
		</body>
	</article>
  <article>
		<title>
			<h1>Shinedown: we've already recorded a new album</h1>
		</title>
		<header>
			<h2>There’s no doubt that Shinedown‘s Brent Smith is a
			prolific writer, but it appears as though he and his 
			hard-working band have gotten ahead of the game for
			their next album.</h2>
		</header>
		<image>
			"latest\article2.jpg" alt="Brent Smith"
		</image>
		<caption>
			Brent Smith of Shinedown talks about their upcoming album
		</caption>
		<body>
			<p>Despite releasing ‘Amaryllis’ earlier this year, S
			mith reveals to NME that the band has already recorded 
			a new album.</p>

			<p>The singer told the Brit-mag in a video interview, 
			“I’ve thought about new material. It’s funny because
			… and you’re actually the very first person I’ll tell
			this too … We’ve actually, we have another record of
			material. It’s actually recorded.”</p>

			<p>Speaking about the new music, Smith explained, 
			“It’s still very massive. It has a very epic feel to
			it, but the tempos are a little slower and the subject
			matter is a little different. I would say it’s actually
			a bit darker — a little bit more mischievous.”</p>

			<p>While the next album is ready, there’s still plenty 
			of life in ‘Amaryllis,’ as the group is taking the 
			opportunity to promote it in other parts of the world. 
			The singer revealed, “This was the first true 
			international record we received, and I say received
			because it really is an honor and it’s a gift and a
			privilege to get an opportunity from your record label 
			to be released internationally, because not every band
			or every artist gets that opportunity.”</p>
		</body>
	</article>
	<article>
		<title>
			<h1>Slash: 'I caught my mum naked with David Bowie'</h1>
		</title>
		<header>
			<h2>Guitarist opens up about his mother's relationship 
			with the Thin White Duke</h2>
		</header>
		<image>
			"latest\article3.jpg" alt="Slash"
		</image>
		<caption>
			Slash playing live..
		</caption>
		<body>
			<p>The legendary axeman, who released his second solo
			album 'Apocalyptic Love' in May, revealed to Australian
			radio station Triple M that he walked in on his 
			costume-designer mother Ola Hudson and the glam
			rock icon in the nude together when he was just
			eight years old. </p>

			<p>Ola, who passed away in 2009, worked with Bowie in
			the mid-1970s and designed his outfits during his 
			period with his 'Thin White Duke' persona, which included
			the album 'Station To Station' and the film The Man
			Who Fell To Earth. </p>

			<p>Speaking about this, Slash said: "My mum started
			working with David professionally at first. I'm 
			pretty sure that’s how it started. Then it turned
			into some sort of mysterious romance that went on
			for a while after that. She did his wardrobe for 
			his whole Thin White Duke period and The Man Who 
			Fell To Earth movie that he did. She did all that
			and he was around for a while."</p>
			
			<p>He continued: "He was always over – they were 
			always together. I caught them naked once. They had
			a lot of stuff going on, but my perspective was 
			limited. Looking back on it, I know exactly what was
			going on. When I look back on that whole combination 
			of people, I can only imagine how freaky it was."</p>
		</body>
	</article>
 </articles>